Guide to the Dwight and Ferris Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Dwight Family Papers, 1711-1834; Series III; 8
  - Genealogies of the Dwight Family, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Printed chart and manuscript diagram
  - First Parish Church, Northampton, record of a dispute between Mr. Dwight and Decon Shelding, 1711 Apr 6 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Signed by Ebenezr Pumry, William King, and Benjamin Wright
  - Photostatic copy of invoice from Thomas Hancock for material purchased by Captain Timothy Dwight (1726-1777), 1762 Aug 26 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Papers of Eleanor Augusta Ferris, 1903-1951; Series IV; 31
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Barrett, A. Maud H., 3 TLS, 1944-47 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - B general, 1947-49 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - C general, 1947-48 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Courtney, [Clare?], 2 ALS and autograph poem, 1940 Jun 14, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Dwight, A. B. [her aunt], [1903?] May 30 (Box 3, Folder 66)
      Concerning Theodore Dwight (1796-1866)
    - Galsworthy, Ada Cooper
      - Letters, "Handcrafts Certificate," photograph of her house Bury, and small gift items (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - Letters, 1921-23 (Box 3, Folder 68)
      - Letters, 1924-28 (Box 3, Folder 69)
      - Letters, 1930-33 (Box 3, Folder 70)
      - Letters, 1937-38 (Box 3, Folder 71)
      - Letters, 1939-40 (Box 3, Folder 72)
        Photo of AG in letter 1940 Dec 11
      - Letters, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 73)
      - Letters, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Letters, 1943-45 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - Letters, 1946-47 (Box 4, Folder 76)
        Photo of AG as Christmas greeting 1947; reproduction of photo layout of John Galsworthy with dogs in letter 1946 Feb 15
      - Letters, 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 77)
        Photo of AG in letter 1951 Jul 18
    - Goodman, Mae Winkler, ALS, 1949 Jun 12 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Kerr, Jessica M., 2 TLS, 1946 Sep 15, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Murray, Lily, TLS, 1948 Nov 12 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - New-York Historical Society, ALS from Dorothy Barck, 1951 Jun 13 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Pack, Alice G., TLS, 1948 May 3 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Postcards from various correspondents, including niece Anne Marvin, 1936-42, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Price, Esther Gaskins, wedding invitation with autograph note, [1944] (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Raymond, R. W. [Rossiter W.], 2 TLS and 1 ALS, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      With carbon typescript of biographical sketch of Theodore Dwight (1796-1866) written for the New England Historic Genealogical Society
    - Starr, ALS, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Weybright, Victor and Hildegarde, printed Christmas greeting (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Wilder, Walter Beebe, TLS, 1941 Jan 5 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Wynne, Marjorie, TLS, 1948 Jul 28 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      With EF's reply 1948 Jul 30; concerns transcription of a letter to Timothy Dwight (1694-1771) by the library; with correct transcription [by EF?] and typescript
  - JOHN GALSWORTHY EPHEMERA
    - Photograph, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Printed supplement from John's O'London's Weekly about the author and his work, 1928 Dec 8 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Reproduction of portrait print by Sullivan, framed, [1930] (Box 4, Folder 92)
- Other Ferris Family Papers, ca. 1875-1941; Series V; 7
  - Isabel Stuart Ferris, postcards from various correspondents, 1940-41 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Mary Dwight Ferris, postcards from various correspondents, 1924-40 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    Includes one card from niece Anne Marvin, and 2 from Mary to "Dearest B."
  - Genealogical notes about the Ferris and Whiting families, and summary of the Ferris sisters' Dwight lineage (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Esther Stoddard Edwards (1672-1770), mother of Jonathan Edwards, photograph of portrait painting, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Photographs, ca. 1875-1905 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    Studio portraits of Augusta Dwight Ferris, [Sherwood Bissell Ferris?], and their daughters as children and young women; one informal photo of the family; two of [Isabel?] with friends; [and portraits of a man other than Sherwood Ferris?]
  - Photographs of the wedding of Anna Edwards Ferris to Charles Ingalls Marvin, [1902 Sep] (Box 4, Folder 98)
    Small paper album and one mounted photo; photos of the wedding party include Eleanor, Mary and Isabel
  - Photographs, ca. 1910-40 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    Informal snapshots of the Ferris sisters with friends and family, pets, houses, and landscapes; one portrait of [Sherwood B. Ferris with Anna and Anne Marvin?]; portrait of unidentified woman; two enlarged snapshots of unidentified child
- Oversize, 5
  - Passport of Theodore Dwight (1794- 1866) (Series II), 1821 Apr 21 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Genealogy of the Dwight Family (Series III), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Belcher, J., to Timothy Dwight (1694- 1771), fragment regarding the boundaries of Northfield (Series I), 1732 Jun 15 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Dwight, Jonathan, ALS to Timothy Dwight (1694-1771) (Series I), 1763 Jul 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - A. B. from Yale College awarded to Theodore Dwight (1794-1866) (Series II), 1814 Sep 14 (Box 5, Folder 104)
- Restricted Fragile, 1
  - Box 1, Folder 42, 1763 (Box Port, folder 105)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material in Port 105. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.